shahzamanlive2@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Medium | Portfolio

### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with a background in developing efficient software applications in a global market. 4+ years of industry experience, including mentoring 10+ junior developers to achieve concrete goals on a strict deadline. Strong skills include React, Next js, Nest js, and Node js. Proficient in problem-solving, collaborating in remote teams and quickly learning new languages.

#### **SKILLS**

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, Next js, HTML5, CSS3, Saas, Material UI, Tailwind, Figma

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, Postgres, Prisma, Express, MongoDB, Nest js

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

## **Full Stack Developer**

May 2023 - Present

★ Health Clinic: - Intuitive user interface for interacting with a medical booking system.

**Built With:** (React, Redux Toolkit, Ruby on Rails, and PostgreSQL)

★ Weather App: - A web app that allows users to explore air quality and weather data for various regions.

**Built With:** (React, Redux Toolkit)

# COGNITIVE HEALTHCARE INTERNATIONAL

Islamabad

## **Full Stack Developer**

Jul 2021 - Present

- ★ Optimized 5+ backend systems, cutting response time by 20%.
- ★ Managed project timelines effectively, delivering 100% of projects on schedule, and showcasing strong self-discipline.
- ★ Guided junior developers on development strategies and innovative techniques.

### ON2SOL (PVT) LIMITED

Islamabad

# Front End Developer

Jan 2019- Jul 2021

- ★ Designed and implemented a strategic plan, enhancing cohesion and streamlining development.
- ★ Enhanced development efficiency by 30%, ensuring timely delivery of new features for future projects.

# +VISION

Islamabad

# UI Developer | UI/UX Designer

May 2018 - Jan 2019

- ★ Implemented a design system for future projects, ensuring consistency through collaborative development.
- ★ Fixed bugs with code, design patterns, and miscellaneous occurrences during the project.

### **EDUCATION**

### **MICROVERSE**

Jul 2023 - Dec 2023

#### Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full-Time

- ★ Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- ★ Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

Air University

Sep 2013 - May 2018